<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>web-development on AMKS</title>
    <link>https://www.amks.me/tags/web-development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in web-development on AMKS</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>amk © 2020</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 18:02:07 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.amks.me/tags/web-development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Recreating Promises in Javascript</title>
      <link>https://www.amks.me/blog/promises/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 18:02:07 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.amks.me/blog/promises/</guid>
      <description>The Promise class is one of the most notoriously black-boxed tools in Javascript. How does the promise class manage asynchronicity, when Javascript is single-threaded?
I made a small Promise class to try to understand. The complete implementation is at the end of this article.
This article assumes some familiarity with the concept of Promises. If you&amp;rsquo;re unfamiliar with Promises, I&amp;rsquo;d highly consider checking out this wonderful guide.
The Specification To focus on core concepts, we&amp;rsquo;ll assume that our Promises always resolve and return a value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making My Own Clipboard</title>
      <link>https://www.amks.me/blog/clipboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2020 05:31:37 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.amks.me/blog/clipboard/</guid>
      <description>Last weekend, I made a private clipboard. You can play with it here and I explain the process of making it in this blog!
⌘+C. ⌘+V. I do this way too many times a day, at an instinctual level. I don&amp;rsquo;t know when I learned how to copy and paste, but it certainly feels like I&amp;rsquo;ve known it all my life. The clipboard is probably the most widely used shortcut on the keyboard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Types of APIs</title>
      <link>https://www.amks.me/blog/apis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 17:49:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.amks.me/blog/apis/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re at all interested in back-end web development, then you&amp;rsquo;ve heard of APIs –– but what are they really?
What are APIs? Imagine that we want to make available data about movies. getLastBlockbuster() returns the last big cinema hit, movieRating(&#39;Parasite&#39;) returns the imdb rating of the movie Parasite, and so on. This would be a very cool tool to give movie enthusiasts! So you go ahead and write this. How do we make this available to users?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pure CSS Solution For Dark Mode</title>
      <link>https://www.amks.me/blog/dark-mode-css/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 20:50:10 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.amks.me/blog/dark-mode-css/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re using any node-based framework, you can use the package I created instead. I also wrote about it.
No Toggle Solution CSS provides a media query to let your website match the preference of the user.
/* Other Styles Here */ ... @media (prefers-color-scheme: dark) { h1 { color: white; } /* Other Selector Style Updates */ ... } Toggle Solution Fundamental Idea: use the CSS + selector to match sibling items with a checkbox label.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building A Dark Mode NPM Package</title>
      <link>https://www.amks.me/blog/dark-mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.amks.me/blog/dark-mode/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve always been a light mode person. I like the cleanliness of it.
But I&amp;rsquo;ve recently developed a fascination with dark mode. It&amp;rsquo;s a feature which has been getting progressively more accepted into the internet development community. The following products went low light in the last couple years: apple, facebook, youtube, instagram, twitter, gmail, slack, soundcloud, google chrome. Here&amp;rsquo;s a convenient exhaustive list.
So I decided to add dark mode to one of my websites that I knew would get a lot of traction.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>